

jeremy.w.barnes@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/jeremywbarnes
jbpkp07.github.io/portfolio

+1 (818) 203-1393
Studio City, CA

About

Software engineer with bachelor's degree in computer science and 4 years of experience in software development. Currently developing a full stack TypeScript/React/AWS cloud application that implements video encoding and delivery. Looking for a mid-level software development role on a team of highly driven engineers to learn, create and problemsolve in a collaborative environment. A self-reliant, curious engineer who strives to leave code better than it was found.

Skills

Programming TypeScript, JavaScript, C#, Java, SQL, PowerShell, Windows Batch, Visual Studio Code, Git, Jira

Frontend React, React Hooks, jQuery, Electron.js, HTML5, CSS, Fluent UI, Bootstrap

Backend Node.js, AWS, Heroku, Express.js, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch, Firebase, MySQL, SQL Server

Work Experience _

Software Engineer | Spafax | Hollywood, CA / Remote

August 2018 - Present

- Collaborated remotely to design, code and deploy backend microservices and user-centered frontend pages for video ingestion, transcoding and delivery from the cloud using TypeScript/React/AWS.
- Researched AWS offerings and developed a prototype application to persuade senior management to migrate onpremise video production to the cloud, improving scalability and reliability.
- Coordinated with music team and developed a desktop application that implements a fully automated audio encoding and delivery pipeline, reducing the overhead cost of 2 employees.
- Coded advanced fuzzy search algorithms to match employee-scheduled music content with 2 million unique audio source files, achieving a long-term accuracy rate of 99.7%.
- Eliminated critical production bottleneck by liaising with content ingestion team and developing software to automate large file movement 300% faster to the on-premise production network.
- Leveraged knowledge in TypeScript, JavaScript, C#, PowerShell, Node.js, React, jQuery, AWS, MongoDB, Git, Jira

Systems Engineer | Spafax | Hollywood, CA

January 2014 – July 2018

- Redesigned and relocated datacenter to increase video file delivery from 300 to 6000 files per month though widespread network, storage and encoding optimizations.
- Transitioned legacy tape-based video workflows to fully digital workflows with 100% MPAA security compliance significantly improving delivery time.
- Directed and mentored a junior team member throughout several projects related to the support of day-to-day IT operations for 2 internal networks, 60 servers, and 100 workstations.
- Leveraged knowledge in TCP/IP, VLAN, firewall security, SANs, 10GE/fiber, H.265 encoding, Windows Server, AD

Software Application Support Engineer | Spafax | Orange, CA

July 2011 – December 2013

Software Engineer | DataPath | San Diego, CA

November 2006 - June 2008

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | UCLA Extension | Westwood, CA

June 2019 – November 2019

4.0 GPA, Top of class

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science | Bucknell University | Lewisburg, PA